Speaker 1: is the author of the new
Speaker 2 (higher-pitched voice): book true and constant friends love and inspiration from our grandmothers mothers and friends and she just so happens to be the wife of presidential candidate rand paul kelly uh... welcome to the show it's good to have you on how does it feel uh... being the wife of a presidential candidate
so far
Speaker 2 (higher-pitched voice): It's not too bad. It's pretty exciting. I'm having a good time with it. Yeah. Some people say it's a little grueling, so get ready. But we're glad to have you on the show. The book looks amazing. I understand your grandmother inspired the book. And before we get into what exactly the inspiration was, she apparently gave you all kinds of things, and she had a huge love of fashion. And there's a purse in particular of hers that you took to the White House. It always
Speaker 4: goes back to purses with me.
I love
Speaker 2 (higher-pitched voice): it.
Speaker 5: Yes. My grandmother, she came to this country in 1929 from Ireland. She worked as a maid for the founders of the Saks Fifth Avenue stores. As her first job, she was a live-in maid. She worked for a lot of wealthy families in New York, and she would always bring me wonderful things when she would come to visit during my childhood, one of which was that beaded purse which one of her employers had given her.
Speaker 5: And when she gave it to me I was about 15 and I'll never forget she told me that she thought that I would take it lots of wonderful places and it was very special to her and she wanted me to have it. My grandmother had a beautiful lyrical way of speaking and she always made a big production out of everything. She was very dramatic and I just remember her giving me that purse and so it's been something that I do want to take special places and the first time I took
Speaker 6: it to the White House I felt like she was there with me.
Speaker 7: Dramatic, great storyteller.
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): I read that she embellished stories. Who would have a guess she came from Ireland? But
Speaker 9: anyway, you know, you also talk about your friends, though. Your friends are an inspiration of this book. This book is about women who actually get together every year. And you guys talk about all your problems and share your problems, whether it's divorce or you say abusive husbands or just problems in life. Talk about how
Speaker 11: that inspired this book as well.
Speaker 10: Very much so. We're a source of support for each other through the tough
Speaker 12 (higher-pitched voice): times, but also all the great times, too. And there are a group of amazing
Speaker 5: women that I met the very first week of my freshman year in college. And I decided when I started thinking about this book to reach out to them and find out who in their life...
Speaker 5: Like Julia O'Toole, my grandmother was for me. Was there a woman, either a mother,
Speaker 12 (higher-pitched voice): grandmother, aunt, someone who really shaped who they were when they were younger? And it was a great experience going back in time as much as 100 years with each friend and really exploring the women that made us who we are. Lovely. Kelly Kay. Kelly,
Speaker 13 (higher-pitched voice): can I ask you what it's like to be a candidate's wife? Because I've never been one, obviously.
Speaker 14 (higher-pitched voice): But candidate's wife is in this kind of curious position. and the New York Times
Speaker 14 (higher-pitched voice): has a headline which says kelly paul has a task to make rand paul more approachable i mean how weird does that seem
to you
Speaker 15: pretty weird because i don't really look at that as my task obviously that's something that
Speaker 5: a journalist wrote um you know uh it is it is an odd kind of position to be in and i i don't think it's just women that are in this position i'm friends with some senate spouses that are that are males in dc and uh being a spouse you're in this
Speaker 5: kind of semi-public position. I still feel like I'm just primarily, you know, Rand's spouse and there to support him and our family. But at the same time, people are curious about who he is as a person. So that kind of gets me out in the spotlight some. And I'm happy to do that. I'm very proud of Rand.
-
Speaker 16: And happy to defend him and some of the charges that he has a problem with
women.
Speaker 5: Absolutely. I mean to me the whole gender angle on that was a bit of a false construct. I mean that's not who Rand is as a person. He wrote the foreword in my book and he talks about all of the women in his life and his whole family is full of strong women. Three female doctors, veterinarian, chemical engineer. His longtime partner in his ophthalmology practice is a female surgeon that he
Speaker 12 (higher-pitched voice): worked with for over 10 years. So Rand is someone who truly looks at the the substance of a person,
Speaker 12 (higher-pitched voice): their intellect and their ideas and is the last person to
Speaker 17: ever judge someone based on their gender or anything else. And
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): Mika, that lines up with what you said after the Savannah Guthrie interview. You said it's not about women. They can take
Speaker 13 (higher-pitched voice): care of themselves. Savannah was fine. Yeah. I actually, I thought there was a good strategy going there, one that you often use, but that's for another
Speaker 2 (higher-pitched voice): day. The book is True and Constant Friends. Kelly Paul, thank you so much for being on. Kelly, thank you. We greatly appreciate it. Thank you so much for having me.
Speaker 19: Good luck out there.